<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Structural Analysis | Mahmoud Ammar</title>
    <link>/tag/structural-analysis/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/structural-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Structural Analysis</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hufd51855d62eaf479e888c08860b63d40_58678_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Structural Analysis</title>
      <link>/tag/structural-analysis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Wind Analysis of The High-Rise Building JPMorgan Chase Tower Using the Eurocode Standard and CFD Simulations</title>
      <link>/project/wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/wind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main task of this project was to conduct a CFD analysis of the high-rise building JPMorgan Chase Tower, Houston, Texas, USA. Historical wind velocities for the previous 72 years were collected from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration database and an analytical aerostatic and aerodynamic analysis using the Eurocode was performed on the building. In this work, GiD was employed for the pre-processing step of the case and CFD analysis was done using KRATOS, an open-source project developed by the chair of Structural Analysis at TUM and the International Center for Numerical Methods in Engineering (CIMNE) in Barcelona, Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isogeometric analyis of trimmed membrane structures</title>
      <link>/project/trimmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/trimmed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The task was to extend a given code for the IGA of untrimmed membranes to the application of trimmed IGA. IGA uses the CAD information as an analysis model, instead of constructing a separate computational model. In order to get accurate results, a k-refinement is performed on the geometrical model. To represent complex geometries trimmed NURBS geometries are employed. In this present work, form finding is done on trimmed membrane surfaces. This project is implemented using MATLAB for the analysis and Rhino to define the geometries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
