<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Desiccation Tolerance | Ahmad Ammar</title>
    <link>/tag/desiccation-tolerance/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/desiccation-tolerance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Desiccation Tolerance</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_huf177042bf29a2329382d4ae41daade7e_1822_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Desiccation Tolerance</title>
      <link>/tag/desiccation-tolerance/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of ELIP genes in the desiccation tolerant Lindernia brevidens and its desiccation sensitive counterpart Lindernia subracemosa.</title>
      <link>/project/master/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/master/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the many studied abiotic stresses, extreme light stress (high or low) represents a huge challenge for food production, namely due to the prevailing combinatorial effects of extreme light and dehydration during the summer season. This work will provide more insights into the stress-responsive genes of the newly sequenced genomes of the homoiochlorophyllous desiccation tolerant L. brevidens and its desiccation sensitive counterpart L. subracemosa. The Master thesis aims at identifying several light-responsive genes, namely the ones coding for the Early Light-induced Proteins (ELIPs) in addition to analyzing both their transcript expression profiles and amino acid sequences. ELIPs are expressed as a result of the combinatorial effect of illumination with high incident light and desiccation treatment. They are involved in protecting the photosynthetic apparatus by binding to Chl a and preventing its degradation. Thereby indirectly protecting the plant from photooxidative stress by preventing the formation of triplet chlorophyll, a potent photosensitizer that causes oxidative damage by converting harmless molecular oxygen into harmful singlet oxygen. The analysis will include comprehensive comparisons between the regulation of ELIP gene expression in the resurrection plant L. brevidens, L. subracemosa, other ELIPs belonging to the family of Linderniaceae, and some homologous protein members of the CAB/ELIP/HLIP superfamily of distantly related polypeptides. Ultimately, the road will be paved for other researchers to use the provided data to explore the crosstalk between dehydration and light stress as well as explore new frontiers to exploit this crosstalk. This research can provide leads to more efficiently breed concurrent tolerance to crops without damaging the performance of plants nor curtailing their yields.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
