<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python | Mahmoud Ammar</title>
    <link>/tag/python/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Python</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hufd51855d62eaf479e888c08860b63d40_58678_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>/tag/python/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Wind Analysis of The High-Rise Building JPMorgan Chase Tower Using the Eurocode Standard and CFD Simulations</title>
      <link>/project/wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/wind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main task of this project was to conduct a CFD analysis of the high-rise building JPMorgan Chase Tower, Houston, Texas, USA. Historical wind velocities for the previous 72 years were collected from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration database and an analytical aerostatic and aerodynamic analysis using the Eurocode was performed on the building. In this work, GiD was employed for the pre-processing step of the case and CFD analysis was done using KRATOS, an open-source project developed by the chair of Structural Analysis at TUM and the International Center for Numerical Methods in Engineering (CIMNE) in Barcelona, Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space-Time Finite Elements For 1D Heat Equation</title>
      <link>/project/spacetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/spacetime/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An alternate method to model transient PDEs, where time is considered as a dimension, in contrast to the conventional transient FEM, where the space is discretized and a time intrgration scheme is applied. Thus, the 1D problem becomes 2D, and the shape functions are a tensor product of space and time. This approach is advntegous for its exponential convergence in time (when using high order shape functions), the ability to perform local time refinement, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluid-Structure Interaction Simulation with Multiple Interfaces</title>
      <link>/project/fsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/fsi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The report of the project aims to explain the literature review, work flow, and results of a group project. The tasks were to implement different coupling algorithms for two
and three springs systems, for a three coupled beams system, and finally solve an FSI problem with two interfaces. In this present work, the first two tasks were implemented in Python and different relaxation methods were used to compare the results, and the last task was implemented in Python using Kratos Multiphysics for the analysis, and GiD for visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
