<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Production Chamber | Ahmad Ammar</title>
    <link>/tag/production-chamber/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/production-chamber/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Production Chamber</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_huf177042bf29a2329382d4ae41daade7e_1822_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Production Chamber</title>
      <link>/tag/production-chamber/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Multi-Floor Hexagonal Design for the Commercial Hydroponic Production of the Loose-Leaf Lettuce Oscarde (Asteraceae Lactuca Sativa L.)</title>
      <link>/project/bachelor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/bachelor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tremendous amount of research has been conducted in the field of hydroponic systems. Recent research has given rise to new production techniques that are more efficient and self-sustainable than contemporary agricultural plant production practices which leave a negative footprint on the environment. Henceforth, hydroponic systems are emerging as a new technology that could potentially suffice the deficit in agricultural production and supersede conventional agriculture as the primary producer of vegetables. Hydroponic production is becoming an attractive frontier for investors and plethora of studies revealed the benefits of hydroponic systems. The major advantage of hydroponic systems is the tight control over plants’ growth environment. That is, to reach the optimum production capacity, several parameters should be vigilantly controlled and monitored. In this report, the production of Lettuce Oscarde was divided into two stages, the germination and transplantation stages. The Germination of lettuce will incorporate the use of Nutrient Film Technique whereas the production of lettuce will incorporate the novel multi-floor hexagonal design. One Module involved in the production stage will resemble a hexagonal prism. The honeycomb-like structure of the stacked hexagonal prisms will conserve space and increase production. An overview of a production facility with the capacity to germinate as much as 223,200,000 seeds and produce as much as 168,407,424 plants was described.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
